以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的，所以我知道我在哪里
ok so actually I have a I know where
人们正在从事项目和工作
people are working on projects and
您不对任何材料负责
you're not responsible for any material
讲座中的新材料谢谢你
new material in the lectures thank you
来了，但我确实有一些东西
for coming but I do have something in an
重要的话题被修订
important topic which is a revised
关于神经网络构建的版本
version about the construction of neural
了解我们的基本结构
nets the basic structure that we're
我们正在努力，以便开放
we're working with so that's on the open
网页7.1节就是这样
web at section 7.1 that's so
建立神经网真的是它
construction of neural nets really it's
学习功能的构建
a construction of the learning function
f这就是你的功能
f so that's the function that you
通过梯度下降或优化
optimize by gradient descent or
随机梯度下降和你
stochastic gradient descent and you
适用于培训数据，以尽量减少
apply to the training data to minimize
你只是想到它的损失
the loss you so just thinking about it
我写的是一种更有条理的方式
in a more organized way because I wrote
在我知道更多之前的那一节
that section before I knew anything more
而不是现在如何拼写神经网络
than how to spell neural nets but now
我考虑的更重要了
I'm thought about it more so the the key
这一点可以与我所拥有的相比
point may be compared to what I had in
过去是我现在认为这是
the past is that I now think of this as
两组变量X的函数
a function of two sets of variables X
和V.
and V
所以X是权重，V是
so X are the weights and V are the
特征向量样本特征
feature vectors the sample feature
从这样的那些载体来从
vectors from the so those come from the
如果一次训练数据
training data either one at a time if
我们正在做随机梯度下降
we're doing stochastic gradient descent
一次批量大小为1或B
with many batch size one or B at a time
如果我们做的是小批量的B或者
if we're doing mini batch of size B or
整个事情整个时代后如
the whole thing a whole epoch at once if
我们正在进行全面的梯度下降
we're doing full-scale gradient descent
所以那些是特征向量和
so so those are the feature vectors and
这些是那些中的数字
these are the numbers in in those in the
Mait在线性步骤中
Mait in the linear steps where the
权重所以他们的矩阵AK是
weights so they're the matrices a k that
你乘以V乘以和
you multiply by multiply V by and also
你添加的偏向量BK
the bias vectors BK that you add on to
转移的起源可以的，这些都是
shift the origin okay and these are the
这些是你的
and these are it's these that you
优化那些是优化和
optimize those are to optimize and
什么是整体的结构
what's the structure of the whole the
整个学习功能和如何
whole of the learning function and how
你用它来做什么神经
do you use it what what does the neural
净的样子，所以你把你f的
net look like so you you take f of a
第一组重量如此f的第一组
first set of weight so f of the first
权重的设置将A1和B1等等
set of weights would be a1 and b1 so
这是X部分和实际的部分
that's the X part and the and the actual
样本矢量样本矢量
sample vector the sample vectors
在迭代中v为零
v zero in the iteration and this
产生，然后你做非线性
produces and then you do the nonlinear
步骤到每个组件并产生
step to each component and that produces
V一
V one
所以有一个典型的我可以写出来
so there is a typical I could write out
这是什么这里有1V0加V1，因此
what this is here a 1 V 0 plus V 1 so
这两个步骤是线性步骤
that's the two steps are the linear step
你的输入是V0你采取线性
you the input is V 0 you take the linear
使用第一个权重a的步骤
step using the using the first weights a
1和B1然后你采取非线性
1 and B 1 then you take the nonlinear
步骤，这给你V1这样的
step and that gives you V 1 so that's
真的比我上面的线条好，所以我会
really better than my line above so I'll
擦除上面的那条线
erase that line above yep
这样就可以从V0和V0产生V1
so that produces V 1 from V 0 and the
第一重，然后是下一级
first weight and then the next level
输入v1所以我只称这个VK或V.
inputs v1 so I'll just call this VK or V
K减1，我称之为VK好吧
K minus 1 and I'll call this one VK okay
所以k等于1到多少
so so k equal to 1 up to however many
图层URL图层，因此输入为v-0
layers URL layers so the input was v-0
所以你可以说这个V真的是v-0
so this V is really v-0 you could say
而你这是神经网络而且这个
and you this is the neural net and this
是每个输出输出
is the out input and output from each
层然后VL是最终输出
layer and then V L is the final output
从最后一层开始，让我们这样做吧
from the final layer so so let's just do
这里的图片是v-0样本
a picture here here here is v-0 a sample
矢量或如果我们正在做图像
vector or if we're doing image
处理它的所有像素
processing it's all the pixels in in the
图像中的在所述数据和所述
image in the in the in the data and the
这是一个样本的培训
training from one sample this is
一个训练样本，然后你
one training sample and then you
乘以1然后你加上B1和你
multiply by a 1 and you add B 1 and you
取Riu的那个向量，然后给出
take Riu of that vector and that gives
你V2V1抱歉给你V1和
you V 2 V 1 sorry that gives you V 1 and
然后你迭代到最后VL最后
then you iterate to finally V L the last
你最后没有做真正的uu层
layer you don't do real uu at the last
层，所以它只是alVL减1加
layer so it's just al V L minus 1 plus
VL也可能不会做偏置矢量
VL and you may not do a bias vector also
在那一层，但你可能和那个
at that layer but you might and that's
这是最后的输出
this is the finally the output so is
那张照片和照片是这样的
that picture and so that picture is
更清晰的对我比以前要
clearer for me than it was previously to
的权重，以便在区分
distinguish between the weights so in
在梯度下降算法中
the in the gradient descent algorithm
你正在选择的是这些X.
it's these X's that you're choosing the
五世的不是这些由给定
V's are not these are given by the
培训不属于该项目的数据
training data that's not part of the
优化部分不属于它的一部分
optimization part that's not part of its
第6章中的X，你找到了
X in chapter 6 where you're finding the
最佳权重，所以这个X真正的立场
optimal weights so this X really stands
forX代表所有重量
for X stands for the all the weights
你计算达AL为L所以它的
that you compute up to a L be L so it's
这就是所有人的集合
that's that's a collection of all the
权重和重要部分
weights and the important part for
实践的应用是实现
applications for practice is to realize
通常有更多的重量和
that there are often more weights and
然后在权重中有更多组件
more components in the weights then
还有在功能组件
there are components in the feature
在vs中的样本中的向量
vectors in the samples in the vs
通常X的大小大于
so often the size of X is greater than
V的大小是一个有趣的
the size of V which is an interesting
还有那种意想不到的情况
and sort of unexpected situation so
经常我会写那个经常是X的
often I'll just write that often the X's
权重X是否在确定之下
are the weights X's are under determined
因为X的数量超过和
because the number of X's exceeds and
往往远远超过签证的数量
often far exceeds the number of visa
基数的数量
number of the cardinality the number of
这里的权重在A和B中
weights in this is in the A's and B's
而这些都是在样品中
and the these are in the samples in the
训练设定好数字
training set the number well the number
的所有样本的特征
of features of all the samples in the
训练集，所以我会得到新的
training set so I'll get that new
第7.1节有希望在本周开始
section 7.1 up hopefully this week on
在开放的那是开放的设置和
the on the open that's the open set and
我会在那里给你发电子邮件给你
I'll email to you on stellar is there
更多我应该说的，你看
more I should say about this you see
在这里我可以画出画面但是
here the I can draw the picture but of
当然手绘的图片很远
course a hand-drawn picture is far
不如机器绘制的图片
inferior to to a machine drawn picture
但在线图片，但让我这样做
but online picture but let me just do it
所以训练样本有V.
so there's V the training sample has
一些组件，然后他们
some components and then they're
现在乘以这里将是v1
multiplied now here's going to be v1 the
第一层，可以有一个
first in layer and that can have a
不同数量的组件
different number of of of components in
在第一层不同的数量
in the first layer different number of
神经元然后每个来自
neurons and then each one comes from
来自
from the
结的，所以我不会继续下去，但在这里
eze by so I won't keep going here but
但你看到的图片就是这样的
but you you see the picture so there's a
伴侣描述基质的一个
mate that describes a matrix a one that
告诉你那些权重是多少
tells you what the weights are on those
然后有一个b1添加了
and then there's a b1 that's added the
BIOS矢量被添加到所有要获得的内容中
BIOS vector is added to all those to get
v1
the v1
所以v1是1V0加B1和
there's so v1 is a 1 V 0 plus B 1 and
那么这就是现场
then onwards so this this is the spot
我们手工绘制它很明显
we're drawing it by hand is clearly
不如任何其他可行的方式
inferior to any other possible way to do
好吧所以现在我还没有投入
it okay so now I haven't yet put into
图片中的损失功能就是这样
the picture the loss function so that's
要最小化的功能
the function that you want to minimize
那么损失函数究竟是什么呢？
so what is the loss function so we're
选择x2即A和B的全部
choosing x2 that's all the A's and B's
把损失降到最低功能埃尔好了，
to minimize the loss function el okay so
这是SRA教授的这一部分
it's this part that Professor SRA's
讲座是关于他所说的他是el
lecture was about so he he said el is
通常是所有F的有限总和
often a finite sum over all the of F so
十六，这是什么？所以这是
what would that be f of X V I so this is
带权重的输出
the output from the with weights with
来自样本编号I的X中的权重和if
weights in X from sample number I and if
我们正在进行批量处理
we're doing batch processing that is
我们正在做整批一次，然后
we're doing the whole batch at once then
我们计算所有我和那是
we compute that for all I and that's the
计算是荒谬的
computation that's ridiculously
贵，而你去了
expensive and you go instead to
随机渐变，你只需选择
stochastic gradient and you just choose
其中一个或那些B.
one of those or B of those
少数就像30到1208
small number be like 30 to 120 8 of
这些F但是全尺度渐变
these F's but but full-scale gradient
下降选择权重X到
descent chooses the weights X to
现在最小化损失所以法律我
minimize the loss now so the law I
没有这方面的损失现在还没有出现
haven't got the loss here yet there is
这个功能损失将是负数
this function the loss would be minus
样本II的真实结果不是
the true result from sample I I don't
写我没有好的记谱
write I haven't got a good notation for
我愿意接受建议
that I'm open to suggestions
那我该怎么写空气呢？
so how do I want to write the air
假设我是这样的话
suppose suppose I'm so that would be if
这可能是最不正方形
it was least squares I would maybe be
平衡，这将是一个总和
squaring that so that would be a sum of
所有的误差平方
squares of errors squared over all the
样品或如果我做随机
samples or if I'm doing stochastic
梯度下降我会尽量减少我
gradient descent I would minimize I
我猜我最小化了这个但是
guess I'm minimizing this but the
问题是我是否使用整个功能
question is do I use the whole function
L在每次迭代中或者我只是选择
L in at each iteration or do I just pick
要查看的样本中的一个或仅两个
one or only B of the samples to look at
在迭代次数K所以这就是
at iteration number K so so this is the
这是X的L然后我加起来了
this is the L of X then I've added up
所有V的所以只是为了保持他们的
over all the V's so just to keep their
符号直接我有这个功能
notation straight I have this function
X和Vs我找到它的输出
of X and V s I find its output
会是什么V这是什么什么的
what would V what this is what to the
神经网络产生它应该是
neural net produces it's supposed to be
接近我们不希望它的真实
close to the true we don't want it to be
正是我们，我们不希望这是
exactly we we don't expect this to be
完全为零，但它可能是因为
exactly zero but it it could be because
我们有很多权重来实现这一目标
we have lots of weights to achieve that
所以这就是无论如何这将是
so that's what anyway that would be the
损失我们最小化和B平方
loss we minimize and B squared for
平方损失，我想我还没有真正
square loss I guess I haven't really
谈到关于损失的功能
spoken about the about loss functions
让我把这些放在这里
let me just put those here
实际上我这些都是流行的损失
and actually I these are popular loss
功能一是我们所知道的
functions one would be the one we know
最好的广场损失和第二号我
best square loss and number two I've
从来没有见过它直接用过这个
never seen it used quite this directly
将是L一个损失可能是总和
would be the L one loss may be the sum
L的一个规范，这是其中的一些
of L one norms this is some of these
在你知道的l2范数中误差平方
error squared in the l2 norm you know
一个损失可能是我的一些
one loss could be there's some over I of
l1损失，但这不是很好
the l1 losses but that's not a well this
这涉及到具体的其他问题
this comes into specific other problems
像套索，还有其他重要的
like lasso and are there other important
你最小化l1规范的问题
problems you're minimizing an l1 norm
但现在还没有深入学习和三个
but not in deep learning now and three
可能是铰链损失可能你们中的一些人
would be hinge loss probably some of you
比我更了解公式和
know better than I the formula and the
铰链损失背后的背景是它
background behind hinge loss is it for
这是四减一一
this is four minus one one
分类问题而不是四个
classification problems rather than four
这适合回归
that would be appropriate for regression
所以这将是回归然后
so this would be for regression and then
最后对神经最重要
finally the most important for neural
网是交叉熵损失
nets is cross-entropy loss
这是神经网络，所以这是
this is for neural nets so this is
真的是我们最常用的损失功能
really our the most used loss function
在我们和大多数人的设置中
in the and the set up that we are mostly
思考和，我会试着说更多
thinking of and and I'll try to say more
关于之前的过程结束，因此是
about that before the course ends so is
我不知道我没有
that I don't know for me I hadn't got
这笔直
this straight
直到重写该部分而且它是
until rewriting that section and it's
现在以更好的形式下注，但评论是
now bet in better form but comments are
欢迎好，所以刚刚完成
welcome okay and so that just completes
我想说什么，你会看到
what I wanted to say and you'll see the
新的部分之前的任何评论
new section any comments on that before
我完全没问题
I go to a different topic entirely okay
哦，然后问题让我走了之前
oh and then questions let me before I go
这个话题我会告诉你什么
to this topic which I'll tell you what
它就是它的一小部分
it is it's it's it's a short section in
这本名为距离的距离
the book called distance about distance
矩阵和问题是我们是不是
matrices and the question is if we're we
我们在太空中有一堆点
have we have a bunch of points in space
而我们所知道的是我们知道的
and what we know is we know the
点和它之间的距离
distances between the points and it's
方便谈论距离
convenient to talk about distances
平方在这里
squared here
好的，我们怎么知道这些
okay and how would we know these
距离可能是雷达或任何
distances maybe by radar or or any
测量他们可能是传感器
measurement they might be sensors which
我们已经放置了，我们可以衡量
we've placed around and we can measure
他们和他们之间的距离
the distances between them and the
问题是他们的立场是什么
question is what's their position so
那是啊，这就是问题等等
that's the yeah that's the question so
让我谈谈这个问题
let me talk a little bit about this
问题，然后暂停找到位置
question and then pause find positions
太空了，但我不知道
and well in space but I don't know we
提前不知道是否
don't know ahead of time maybe whether
空间是普通的3d空间或
the space is ordinary 3d space or
这些是飞机上的传感器还是
whether these are sensors in a plane or
我们是否要走得更高
whether we have to go to higher
尺寸我只是把D和我们放在一起
dimensions I'll just put D and and we
我也会说我们也是
also I'll just say then we're also
找到D以及这些职位是什么
finding D and what are these positions
这些是XXI的位置所以
these are positions X X I so the
XI减去XJ平方之间的距离是
distance between X I minus XJ squared is
是给定的DIJ所以我们给了
is the given D IJ so we're given
它们之间的距离和我们想要的距离
distances between them and we want to
找到他们的位置找到他们所以我们
find their positions find their so we
知道距离，我们想找到
know distances and we want to find
这是问题的立场
positions that's the question and it's
只是一个解决的简洁数学问题
just a neat math question that is solved
你会看到一个完整的解决方案
and you'll see a complete solution and
它有很多应用程序，它是
and it has lots of applications and it's
是的它只是一个很好的它是一个很好的
yeah it's just a nice it's a nice
问题所以它占据了一部分
question so it occupies a section of the
但那部分只有两页
book but that section is only two pages
很长一段时间，因为它只是一个简单的
long because it's just a straightforward
给出了这个问题的解决方案
solution to that question given the
距离找到给定的位置
distances find the positions given the
距离找到XS
distances find the XS
好的，所以我会谈论那个让我们
okay so I'm gonna speak about that let
我有一个很好的建议
me I had a suggestion a good suggestion
通过电子邮件
by email
关于项目即将来临的问题
well questions about the projects coming
在项目中开始进入和
in projects are beginning to come in and
至少在一开始我就是这样做的
at least at the beginning I'm I make
在所有情况下开始和结束都很好
well out in all cases beginning and end
我会仔细阅读它们
I'll read them carefully and as long as
我可以退后一步的建议
I can I'll stand back suggestions for
我们的最终重写和我说，所以我想
our final rewrite and as I said so I'd
希望得到一个打印出来是伟大的你
like to get a print out is great you
可以把它留在外面的信封里
could leave it in the envelope outside
我的办公室
my office
但当然在线就是这样
but of course online is it's what
每个人都这样做，这些都是公正的
everybody's doing so those are just
开始进来，他们不是
beginning to come in and they're not if
我们可以从今天起一周内把它们送进去
we can get them in by a week from today
我真的很开心，只是
I'm really really happy yep and just
随时给我发电子邮件我会给我发电子邮件
feel free to email me I would email me
关于项目而不是乔纳森
about projects rather than not Jonathan
而且我认为并非匿名恒星
and not not anonymous stellar I think
你可能最好问问我
you probably better just ask me that
问题那很好，我会试试
question that's that's fine and I'll try
以有用的方式回答你
to answer you in a useful way
是的，所以我总是愿意接受
yeah so that's and I'm always open to
问题所以你可以给我发电子邮件
questions so you could email me like how
该项目应该是我的导师
long should this project be my tutor in
牛津说他喜欢什么
Oxford said something like when he you
知道你在写论文
know you were writing essays that's the
牛津系统是写一篇文章和
Oxford system is to write an essay and
他说只是从它开始的地方开始
he said just start where it starts and
当它结束时就结束了
end when it finishes so that's the
这就是主意
that's the idea
肯定不会长，然后一个
certainly not normally long and then a
问题被提出，我可以问你是否
question was raised and I can ask you if
你有兴趣在
you are interested in that
问题是此后的课程
the question was what courses after this
一个是自然的，有点自然
one are natural are sort of natural to
采取前进，我不知道如何
take to go forward and I don't know how
很多人
many of you
谁想要有时间
who are thinking to take have time to
另外还有麻省理工学院的其他MIT课程
take another MIT other MIT courses in
这个领域的深度学习机器
this area of deep learning machine
学习优化所有主题
learning optimization all the topics
我们这里有人想要带走
we've had here anybody expecting to take
更多的课程只是伸出一只手是啊
more courses just stick up a hand yeah
你已经知道麻省理工学院了
and you already know like what MIT
提供或者使被质疑，认为
offers or so that was the question that
来找我麻省理工学院提供的内容
came to me what does MIT offer in this
方向，我没有抬头看
direction and I haven't looked up to see
roz课程sra的教授人数
the number of professors roz course sra
但在六天之后它就是六点
but after in course six it's six point
数量很高，并且在他的好之后
high number and and after his good
讲座我认为这是必须的
lecture I think that's gotta be
值得的，所以我看了六个课程
worthwhile so I looked on course six I
没找到一个非常非常的研究所
didn't find a really very an institute
广泛的名单可能当然六感觉
wide list maybe course six feels that
他们是研究所，但还有其他
they are the Institute but there's other
周围的课程，但我发现在
courses around and but I found in in the
操作是一个搜索网站哦，看到了
operations were a search site oh are see
运营研究中心让我
the operations Research Center let me
只是把它放在那里以防万一你
just put there this is just in case you
我想考虑其中的任何一个
would like to think about any of these
我写的东西就这样，所以我
things so there as I write that so I
听过Timberners-le的演讲
heard the lecture by Tim berners-lee
这里的其他人认为这一周左右
that others here that this a week or so
之前他创建了网络，所以它很漂亮
ago he created the web so it's a pretty
惊人
amazing
毕竟，这不是AlGore，你知道
it wasn't Al Gore after all and you know
你知道他的名字，他现在就是爵士
do you know his name what he's now Sir
蒂姆伯纳斯利这么双名
Tim berners-lee so that double name
让你怀疑他是来自英格兰
makes you suspect it's he's from England
比他还要他，但我是这样的人
than he is but he so anybody I was going
说他是我让他负责
to say he's I hold him responsible for
这些
these
地址中的过多字母
excessive letters in in the address in
URL我的意思是他让我们都说www
the URL I mean he's made us all say www
一年或找其他方式说
for a year or find some other way to say
它但是说我觉得没关系并不容易
it but it's not easy to say I think okay
无论这是什么操作或
whatever this is the operate the o.r
麻省理工学院的中心，然后是学术界或
Center at MIT and then it's academics or
什么，然后它就像
something and then it's something like
课程设置大约
course offerings that's approximately
权，因为它们适用于
right and since they do apply to
优化，你知道有一个
optimization that's you know there's a
蚂蚁数据分析的标题或
heading of ant data analytics or
统计数据有优化
statistics there's optimization there's
oo-或运营研究其他清单
o-o-or operations research other lists
但是许多课程都很好
but a good list of courses from many
部门担任总裁
departments as president
尤其是如此特别是当然的缘故
especially so especially course sakes
当然15这是哪里
of course 15 which is where the
运营研究中心是课程
operations Research Center are is course
18当然也有其他人
18 and there are others in course too
和其他地方的好耶有人会
and elsewhere yeah well would somebody
想说出你的想法
like to say what course you have in mind
如果你，请在此之后接下一个
to take next after this one if you
看着明年的展望
looked at the looked ahead to next year
什么样的建议
any many suggestions of what looks like
一个好的课程，你知道我只知道我
a good course I I you know I only know I
坐在6.03六点六真的基本
sat in once on 6.03 six the really basic
当然，你想要去
course and you you would want to go
更高的好，我不会有任何可能这是
higher okay I I won't any maybe this is
只是说我有兴趣知道
just to say I'd be interested to know
接下来你的经历是什么
what you do next what your experience is
或者我很乐意提供建议但也许
or I'd be happy to give advice but maybe
我的一般建议是那是一个
my general advice is that that's a
有用的清单
useful list of
课程还可以回到距离
of courses okay back to distance
矩阵没关系，所以这就是问题所在
matrices okay so here's the problem
是的，我可能不得不提高
yep okay I'll probably have to raise
但是我会把它留下一分钟好吧
that but I'll leave it for a minute okay
所以我们知道这些距离，我们想要
so we know these distances and we want
找到出口
to find the exit
所以我们可以这样称呼DIJ吧
so let's call this D IJ maybe so we have
一个D矩阵，我们想找到
a D matrix and we want to find the
位置矩阵让我看看是什么
position matrix let me just see what
符号所以这是3.9节no4.9
notation so this is section 3.9 no 4.9
以前3.9，但章三
previously 3.9 but chapters three and
四个人切换了，也许也许
four got switched so and maybe maybe
实际是的，我认为这是八或
actually yeah I think it's it's eight or
九点或十点其他主题正在尝试
nine or ten it's other topics are trying
找到他们的方式，好吧，这就是
to find their way and okay so that's the
这是在该地段上的参考
that's the reference on the lot on the
网页，我会把这些部分放到
web and I'll get these sections onto
恒星好吧所以问题是我们可以
stellar okay so the question is can we
从距离恢复位置
recover the positions from the distances
其实还有一个问题是
in fact there's also a question are
从给定的位置总是有位置
there always positions from the given
距离所以让我和我提到
distances so let me and and I mentioned
我已经说过几个应用程序
several applications I've already spoken
关于你的无线传感器网络
about wireless sensor networks where you
你可以衡量之间的旅行时间
you can measure travel times between
它们介于传感器和你之间
them between the sensors and then you
然后给你距离
that gives you the distances and then
你使用这个简洁的数学计算
you use this neat little bit of math to
当然找到你的位置
find the positions well of course you
无法找到唯一的位置
can't find the positions uniquely
显然你可以任何僵硬的动作
clearly you could any rigid motion of
如果我有一套，所有的职位
all the positions if I have a set of
定位我将称之为X的那个
positions what am I going to call that X
所以就在这里
so so right here and then
所以我给了D矩阵
so I'm given the D matrix that's
距离和工作是找到X.
distances and the job is to find the X
给出位置和的矩阵
matrix which gives the positions and
我要说的和你在一起
what I'm just going to say and you
已经看到，看到它在你的心中
already saw that saw it in your mind
如果我有一套职位我
that if I have a set of positions I
可以做距离的翻译
could do a translation the distances
不会改变，或者我可以做一个僵硬的
wouldn't change or I could do a rigid
运动其他刚性旋转所以位置
motion other rigid rotation so positions
不是唯一的，但我可以让我来
are not unique but I can make I can come
说把中心更近
closer by saying put the center of
原点上的质心或类似的东西
centroid at the origin or something like
这将取消翻译
that that will take out the translations
至少没关系，所以找到X矩阵
at least okay so find the X matrix
这是好的工作，我打算去
that's the job okay and I was going to
在我开始之前的形状
before I start on that the shapes of
分子是核的另一种应用
molecules is another application nuclear
磁共振给出了距离
magnetic resonance gives distances gives
D然后我们找到位置MX和
D and then we find the positions M X and
当然那里有一个噪音
of course there's a noise in there and
有时缺少条目和机器
sometimes missing entries and machine
学习也可以简单地描述为
learning could be just described also as
你给了很多分
a you've given a whole lot of points in
空间特征向量在高
space feature vectors in a high
维空间实际上这是一个很大的空间
dimensional space actually this is a big
交易给你很多积分
deal you're given a whole lot of points
在高维空间的哪里
with where the in high dimensional space
那些与他们有关系
and those are related there they're
他们有点聚在一起
there they sort of come together
自然所以他们倾向于适应
naturally so they tend to fit on a
高维空间中的表面低
surface in high dimensional space a low
高维尺寸表面
dimensional surface in high dimensional
空间和真正的很多数学是
space and really a lot of mathematics is
致力于发现低维度
devoted to finding that low dimensional
那个子空间但它可以是弯曲的
that sub space but it could be curved so
子空间真的不是正确的单词
sub space is not the correct word really
歧管是弯曲的歧管本
manifold is curved manifold this
一个甲基几何学家会说这很接近
a meth geometers would say that is close
所有的行星都平滑而接近
to all the planets smooth and close to
所有的点，你可以线性化它
all the points and you can linearize it
你可以把它弄平，然后你
you could flatten it out and then you
有一个大大减少的问题了
have a much reduced problem the
尺寸从原来减少
dimension is reduced from the original
点的维度
dimension of the of the where the points
谎言有很多数据真实
lie with a lot of data to the true
当然，问题的维度
dimension of the problem which of course
如果积分都是直的
if the points were all on a straight
排列问题的真实维度
line the true dimension of the problem
会是一个
would be one
我们所以我们必须发现这一点
well we so we have to discover this that
我们还必须找到尺寸Dok
we also have to find that dimension D ok
好的，我们怎么做才是这样呢
ok so how do we do it so it's a
经典问题它只是一个整洁
classical problem it just has a neat
回答好吧好吧让我们认识一下
answer ok okay so let's recognize the
距离与之间的联系
connection between distances and
位置所以DIJ是它的长度
positions so D IJ is length of it's the
它们之间的平方距离，从而是
square distance between them so that is
XIXI减去XIXJ减去xjxi加x
X I X I minus X I XJ minus xj x i plus x
JX检查确定是正确的确是如此
JX check ok is that right yes ok so
这些都是DIJ的以矩阵和
those are the DI J's in a matrix and
这些是矩阵Dok中的条目
these are entries in the matrix D ok
这些条目
well these entries
只依靠我，他们是相同的
depend only on I they're the same for
每一个J所以这就是这个意志
every J so this is going to be this will
这部分将产生排名第一
this this part will produce a rank one
矩阵，因为事情只依赖于
matrix because things depend only on the
排J但他们的列号不是这样的
row but not on J their column number so
列重复是的，这产生了
columns repeated yeah and this produces
类似的事情只取决于
a similarly something that depends only
在J上只有列号这样的
on J only on the column number so the
行都是一样的，所以这也是一个
rows are all the same so this is also a
排名一个矩阵，所有重复发送
rank one matrix with all repeated sent
所有相同的行，因为如果我改变我
all the same rows because if I change I
这种内在产品没有任何变化
nothing changes in that inner product so
这些是产生的条款
really these are the terms that produce
大多数矩阵的重要部分
most of the matrix the significant part
矩阵好吗，那我们该怎么办呢
of the matrix okay so what do we do with
那些什么呢
those so what what
让我们看看，我没有，我给一个名字
so let's see I've did I give a name for
我想是我正在寻找的矩阵
the matrix that I'm looking for I think
在笔记中我称之为X所以我得到了
in the notes I call it X so so I'm given
给D找到X，我实际上是什么
D given D find X and what I'll actually
发现你可以看到它来到这里
find you can see it coming here is
实际上找到X转置X因为什么
actually find X transpose X because what
我所拥有的只是点积
all I'm what I'm given is dot products
X的所以我想找到
of X's so so I would like to find to
发现所有这些XI
discover out of out of all this what X I
用XJ点缀是正确的
dotted with XJ is that'll be the correct
点积我们称之为矩阵G.
dot product let's call this matrix G for
然后是点积矩阵
the dot product matrix and then then
从G找到X所以这是一个很好的论点
find X from G so this is a nice argument
所以这告诉我的是一堆
so what this tells me is a bunch of some
有关点积的信息，所以这个
information about dot products so this
告诉我关于G的一些事情
is telling me something about the G
矩阵X的转置矩阵X，然后
matrix the X transpose X matrix and then
一旦我知道G，那么这是一个单独的步骤
once I know G then it's a separate step
找到X，当然就是这样
to find X and of course that's this is
如果，X不是唯一的点
the point of which X is not unique if
如果我把旋转放入X.
there's if I put in a rotation into X
然后旋转Q我会看到Q.
then that rotation Q will I'll see a Q
转置Q它会消失所以
transpose Q and it'll disappear so the
所以我可以自由旋转X.
so the I'm free to rotate the X's
因为这不会改变点
because that doesn't change the dot
产品，但我想要的是G
product but so it's G that I want to
知道，这告诉我关于G的事情
know and this tells me something about G
这告诉我一些关于G和
and this tells me something about G and
那就是这样，但这就是我必须要做的
so does that but that's what I have to
看到那些告诉我的是什么
see so what is what do those tell me
让我们看看让我写下我的内容
let's see let me write down what I have
在这里所以，所以让我们说一个
here so so the the the so let's say a
以VII为内部的对角矩阵
diagonal matrix with VII as the inner
产品XI将XI我们认为
product X I would X I that we that we're
从这里因此让部分信息
getting partial information from here so
所以，我正在介绍那个
so is that okay I'm introducing that
符号，因为现在这样
notation because this is now going to
告诉我，我的D矩阵就是这样
tell me that my D matrix is so what is
这就是对角线矩阵
that so this is the diagonal matrix
也许这只是我应该说的一个载体
maybe it's just a vector I should say
是的，是的，所以我可以写下来
yeah yeah yep so can I write down the
方程那这就是它的
equation that that that's that it's
基本在这里，然后哦，然后我们会
fundamental here and then oh then we'll
找出它意味着什么，所以它是一个
figure out what it means so it's a
点积的G的等式
equation for G for the dot product
矩阵好吧让我为此腾出空间
matrix okay let me make space for that
等式，所以这就是我相信我们
equation so here's the I believe that we
我可以得到点积矩阵
can get the dot product matrix which I'm
按照这个来调用G
calling G as as according to this it's
减去D矩阵的1/2加1/2的1/2
minus 1/2 of the D matrix plus 1/2 of
那些时间D对角线D和
the ones times the D the diagonal D and
它加上了深度的1/2
it's plus 1/2 of the depth of the
时间和曾经这些是矩阵
the times and once these that's a matrix
与恒定行相同
with the same with constant rows that
矩阵就是这就是这个
matrix is that this here is this is
从有这个未来是一个矩阵
coming from there this is a matrix with
总是在同一列，让我看不到
always the same columns so let me see no
我没有得到那些正确的
I haven't got haven't got those right
但我的意思是我希望这些排名第一
yet I mean I want these to be rank one
矩阵，所以我就是这个
matrices so I've it's this one that's
让我解决这个问题一个一个一个一个时间d
let me fix that one one one one times D
转置所以它的列时间排和
transpose so it's column times row and
这个也是列时间行
this one is also column times row with
这里的d现在没事了，让我看看那个
the D here okay now let me look at that
这个家伙的每一行都是合适的
properly so every row in this guy is a
多个一一一
multiple of one one one one
那是什么告诉我所有的
so what does that telling me that all
所有列都是相同的列
columns are the same all columns are
这部分是反映这些
this this part is is reflecting these
列重复的地方
ones where the columns are repeated this
一个是反映这个行的位置
one is reflecting this where the rows
重复D只是D的集合
are repeated the D is just the set of D
让我们称之为di，这就是
numbers let's call that di and this is
DJ所以我和这里都是D矩阵
DJ so all I'm and here's the D matrix
所以这部分D的一部分
so part of the so so part of the D
矩阵是这是这个坑和这个
matrix is is these is this pit and this
现在就是这一点，每个都给一个排名
bit each giving a rank one now it's this
我必须要了解的部分
part that I have to understand
所以，当你检查时，让我来
so let me while you're checking on that
让我好吧，让我们看看我们在哪里
let me okay yep let's just see where we
如果这是真的，如果这是真的我是
are if this is true if this is true I'm
给出D矩阵然后这些点
given the D matrix and then these dot
我能找到的产品，所以我可以找到这些
products I can find so I can find these
换句话说，这是关键
so in other words this is the key
方程式告诉我那就是那个
equation that tells me that's that's the
关键方程，它要来只
key equation and it's going to come just
来自那个简单的身份
from that simple identity just from
我们这个学期检查每个学期
checking each term this term we
确定我们确定的上一学期
identified that last term we identified
现在这个词当然是B好吧
it now this term is B well of course
它是D所以我有两个，我
it's D so I have two of those and I'm
将其中的一半用于
going to take half of half of that to
得到DI认为是的是的，我们将我们
get D I think yep yep and we'll we'll
看起来如此，是的
look so so yeah
所以我想我没有马上看到原因
so I guess I'm not seeing right away why
这一半在这里
this half is in here
但那是，但我认为我做得对
but that's but I think I had it right
并且有一个原因，但你看到了
and there's there's a reason but you see
该矩阵这个X的转置X
that this matrix this X transpose X
矩阵来自这些等级1
matrix is coming from these Rank 1
地方和这些作品
places and these pieces which are the
跨产品哦，哦，我知道我看到什么
the cross-product oh oh I see I see what
真的是那个等式真的
really what that equation is really
说是D矩阵就是这个
saying is that the the D matrix is this
如果我只是阅读并翻译
if I just read that along and translate
它并把它放在矩阵的语言是这个
it and put it in matrix language is this
111112D让我们说
1 1 1 1 the 1 2 D for let's say
转置是这个秩1矩阵和
transpose is this Rank 1 matrix and the
另一种是DS倍11，其是
other one is the DS times 1 1 which is
转换那个然后另一个
the transpose of that and then the other
一个是交叉产品的减2
one was a minus 2 of the cross product
矩阵，所以当我写那个
matrices yep so when I write that
矩阵语言中的方程式我得到了
equation in matrix language I just get
那个，现在当我解决x
that and now when I solve for x
哦，它只是2减2X转置XI
oh it's 2 minus 2 X transpose X I just
是的，对不起
yeah yep sorry
交叉产品XS所以我有一套
cross products the XS so I had one set
交叉产品然后这是
of cross products and then this is the
与此相同所以我减去其中的2个
same as this so I have minus 2 of them
所以现在我只是重写那个
so now I'm just rewriting the that when
我重写了我所做的那个等式
I rewrite that equation I have that do
你知道我把它放在这边我
you see that I put that on this side I
把D放在这里作为减去DI除以
put D over here as a minus D I divide by
2，然后是这样的公式，以便
2 and then that's the formula so
最终这个简单的身份只是
ultimately this simple identity just
看着因为这些碎片是如此
looked at because these pieces were so
简单只是排名一个和这个
simple just rank one pieces and this
这些作品是
these pieces were
实际上我们想要X转置X.
actually what we want the X transpose X
那个方程告诉我们D的G
pieces the G that equation told us the D
我们知道这一切都很清楚，所以这是什么
we know all this is known well so what's
真的是，D和这个已知的是什么
really yeah what's known is D and this
这所以现在我们有公式
and this so now we have the equation for
x转置X是D减去1/2
x transpose X is minus 1/2 of D minus
-这些排名很抱歉让它看起来
- these rank ones sorry to make it look
如果我记得RogeroutT，那就太乱了
messy if I remember that Roger out T
说起去年春天也
talking about a last spring also the
代数变得慌乱，但我们得到了它
algebra got flustered but so we get it
所以我们知道X现在转换X矩阵
so we know X transpose X that matrix now
你能为我们做四分钟吗？
can you just can we just do four minutes
今天结束时线性代数的给出
of linear algebra at the end today given
X转置X找到X这是nbynhow
X transpose X find X this is n by n how
你会做，你能做到这一点会
would you do that could you do it would
只有一个X知道什么是这样的
there be just one X know what so so any
如果你有一个X倍数
if you had if you had one X multiply
通过正交旋转
that by a rotation by an orthogonal
矩阵你还有另外一个所以这个
matrix you'd have another one so so this
你是在寻找X到正交
is you're finding X up to an orthogonal
转型，但你怎么样
transformation but how would you
实际上做得很好我们知道什么
actually do that well what do we know
关于这个矩阵X转置X.
about this matrix X transpose X
对称清晰，特别是我们
symmetric clearly and what we especially
知道它也是正面的或半正面的
know is that it's also positive or semi
确定所以这是半确定的
definite so this is semi definite
所以我给了一个半定矩阵
so I'm given a semi definite matrix and
我想找到一个平方根你可以
I want to find a square root you could
说矩阵是X转置X和
say that matrix is the X transpose X and
我想找到XI认为有两个
I want to find X I think there are two
领先的候选人有很多
leading candidates there are many
候选人，因为如果你找到一个
candidates because if you find one then
然后任何QX都没关系，因为如果我
then any QX is okay yeah because if I
把Q转置Q放在那里就是了
put a Q transpose Q in there it's the
身份好吧所以一种方法是使用本征
identity okay so one way is to use eigen
X转置x和其它的值
values of x transpose x and the other
方法是在X上使用消除
way would be to use elimination on X
移调X以便使用，如果我使用的话
transpose X so so for use so if I use
如果我找到本征，则X的本征值
eigen values of X if I find the eigen
X的值转置X然后我正在写
values of X transpose X then I'm writing
因为它是对称的
this as it's a symmetric
肯定地把它写成Qlambda
positive-definite writing it as Q lambda
Q转置正确，这是根本
Q transpose right that's the fundamental
最重要的定理在附近
most important theorem in the near
代数你可以说是对称的
algebra you could say that a symmetric
正半正定矩阵
positive semi definite matrix has
更大的本征值大于等于零
greater eigen values greater equal zero
和特征向量是正交如此
and eigen vectors that are orthogonal so
现在如果我知道什么是好的X呢
now if I know that what's a good X then
把X变为什么，所以我得到了
take X to be what so I've got the
特征值和X的特征向量
eigenvalues and eigenvectors of X
转置X而我正在寻找X.
transpose X and I'm looking for an X
这将是有效的，一个想法只是为了
that will work and one idea is just to
取相同的特征值特征向量
take the same eigen values eigen vectors
并采取征的平方根
and take the square roots of the eigen
值因为如果我跟踪我是否相乘
values because if I multiply if I track
该对称的现在这是等于X
that symmetric now this is equal to X
颠倒
transpose
如果我这样那就是一个正方形
and if I so that was a that's a square
根符号或λ的二分之一
root symbol or a lambda to the one-half
我可以，我可以这么说，当我乘
I could I could say so when I multiply
我只是X转置X是
that I'm just really X transpose X is
当我把它放在一边时，只是x平方
just x squared here when I square it the
Q转置Q乘以自身给出
Q transpose Q multiplies itself to give
身份是lambdax的平方根
the identity the square root of lambda x
lambda的平方根是那些
times the square root of lambda is those
是给出lambda的对角矩阵
are diagonal matrices that give lambda
我得到了正确的答案，所以有一种方法
and I get the right answer so one way is
用几句话来说就是平方根
in a few words take the square roots of
特征值并保持
the eigenvalues and keep the
特征向量，这是特征值
eigenvectors so that's the eigenvalue
施工，这样就产生了X.
construction so that's producing an X
这是对称的正半确定
that is symmetric positive semi definite
这可能是你想要的东西
that might be what you want it's a
很少工作，因为你在计算
little work because you're computing
这样做的特征值和特征向量
eigenvalues and eigenvectors to do it
但现在我认为这是一个选择
but that's one choice now I believe that
淘汰会给我们另一种选择
elimination would give us another choice
所以消除会产生什么
so elimination produces what
这个因素化仍然是我们的
factorization of this this is still our
对称正定矩阵如果
symmetric positive definite matrix if
你消灭了你
you do elimination on that you you
通常期望L下三角形
usually expect L a lower triangular
时间Z的枢轴次数是上部的
times Z the the pivots times u the upper
三角这就是通常的结果
triangular that's the usual result of of
消除LD你我正在考虑
elimination LD u I'm factoring out the
枢轴所以他们在对角线上的那些
pivots so they're ones on the diagonals
L和U但现在如果它是对称的
of L and U but now if it's symmetric
矩阵怎么了我们通过消除拉链
matrix what's up we zip by elimination
关于这是一个1806琐碎的一点
regarding that as a 1806 trivial bit of
线性代数但当然它是高度的
linear algebra but of course it's highly
重要的是这里的情况如何
important so what's the situation here
当基体是实际上对称的
when the matrix is actually symmetric
U所以我想看看
the U so I want something to look
对称我该如何看待
symmetric how do I make that look
对称的U被L取代
symmetric the U gets replaced by L
如果我转移
transpose if I
如果我，如果我正在做一个积极的
if I if I'm working on a positive
明确说明正定矩阵
definite say positive definite matrix
然后我得到积极的支点和L和
then I get positive pivots and L and
下三角形和上三角形或
lower triangular and upper triangular or
所以现在是什么彼此调换
transposes of each other so now what is
然后
then
什么是X就像那样
then what's the X it's just like that
我将使用DL转置的L平方根
I'll use L square root of D L transpose
是的，等一下，是什么
is that right ooh wait a minute what's
不，因为我不会工作
up no that's not gonna work because I
我没有L转置L我有Q
don't have L transpose L where I had Q
转置Q很好不抱歉让我们得到
transpose Q was good no sorry let's get
完全擦除X部分应该
that totally erased the X part should
只是dL转置的平方根
just be a square root of d L transpose
这就是X现在是我们的
that's that's the X is now our
三角矩阵的平方根
triangular matrix the square root of the
枢轴和L转置部分现在
pivots and the L transpose part and now
当我做X转置X然后你看到
when I do X transpose X then you you see
X转置X正确到达X.
X transpose X coming correctly X
转置将是L将是L转置
transpose will be L will be L transpose
转置会给我L平方根
transpose will give me the L square root
d的d的次平方根会给
of D times square root of D will give
D然后L转置是正确的
the D and then the L transpose is right
所以这叫做我试着写的
so this is called the do I try to write
在这里，这是我今天最后一个字
it here this is my last word for today
乔列斯基那些都是这样的
the cholesky those are the this is the
命名的胆甾醇分解
cholesky factorization named after
实际上是法国士兵的法国人
french guy who a French soldier actually
所以LDL转置是胆怯的，那就是
so LD L transpose is cholesky and that's
这很容易计算得更快
that's easy to compute much faster to
计算比平方的本征值
compute than the eigen value of square
根，但这个方根是三角形的
root but this square root is triangular
这个平方根是对称的
this square root is symmetric those are
的两个排序线性代数的条
the two sort of pieces of linear algebra
寻找减少事物的东西
to find things to reduce things to
三角形或减少它们
triangular form or to reduce them to
用对称矩阵连接它们
to connect them with symmetric matrices
好的，谢谢你今天的关注
okay thank you for attention today so
今天我们做了距离矩阵和
today we did the distance matrices and
这是获得X和X的最后一步
this was the final step to get the X and
也越来越重要了
also getting the more most important was
获得神经网络的结构
to get the structure of a neural net
直分离五世的样本
straight separating the V's the sample
从X的向量权重可以
vectors from the X's the weights okay so
星期五我有一位志愿者在说话
Friday I've got one volunteer to talk
关于一个项目，我很拼命
about a project and I'm desperately
寻找更多请发给我一个
looking for more please just send me an
电邮你在你的它会是
email you're in your your it'll be
appreciated or I'll send you an email if
赞赏或我会发送电子邮件，如果
必要的，谢谢
necessary okay thanks